<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Logic | hziba-hakim</title>
    <link>https://hziba-hakim.github.io/en/tags/logic/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hziba-hakim.github.io/en/tags/logic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Logic</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hziba-hakim.github.io/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Logic</title>
      <link>https://hziba-hakim.github.io/en/tags/logic/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Journal – Week 4 (June 16–22)</title>
      <link>https://hziba-hakim.github.io/en/post/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hziba-hakim.github.io/en/post/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-4-exams-and-final-assessments&#34;&gt;📝 Week 4: Exams and Final Assessments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most intense week of the month. We had the &lt;strong&gt;mathematical logic exam&lt;/strong&gt;. The questions were challenging: propositional logic semantics, formal proofs, and formula minimization methods. I managed it, but had to do a lot of revision beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;calculus&lt;/strong&gt;, one more test remained — on integrals. I’ve been learning to choose substitutions and apply integration by parts. Categorizing problems by type really helps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;programming&lt;/strong&gt;, we began preparing for the final project. The task is to develop a command-line utility in Python that works with text files. I’m currently planning the architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Journal – Week 2 (June 2–8)</title>
      <link>https://hziba-hakim.github.io/en/post/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hziba-hakim.github.io/en/post/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-2-increasing-complexity&#34;&gt;📚 Week 2: Increasing Complexity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week in &lt;strong&gt;calculus&lt;/strong&gt; we had practical sessions on applying derivatives to function analysis. We learned how to find extrema, sketch graphs, and analyze concavity. I realized that visualization is essential — started using graphing calculators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;programming&lt;/strong&gt;, we moved on to working with arrays and strings. It was especially interesting to solve problems related to character counting and sorting — I could feel my algorithmic thinking starting to take shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;logic&lt;/strong&gt;, we focused on formal proofs: axioms, inference rules, deduction. I got a bit tangled up in the formalism, but the instructor gave a helpful breakdown of common mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Journal – Week 1 (May 26 – June 1)</title>
      <link>https://hziba-hakim.github.io/en/post/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hziba-hakim.github.io/en/post/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-week-1-diving-into-the-basics&#34;&gt;✍️ Week 1: Diving into the Basics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week marked the beginning of an in-depth exploration of &lt;strong&gt;mathematical analysis&lt;/strong&gt;: limits, derivatives, and their geometric interpretation. The instructor provided valuable practice on derivatives of complex functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;programming&lt;/strong&gt;, we studied recursion and went through several classical problems: factorial, Fibonacci numbers, binary search. We coded in Python — it became clearer how to call functions recursively and manage stack depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also started a new module in &lt;strong&gt;mathematical logic&lt;/strong&gt; — covering basic logical connectives and building truth tables. It’s fascinating how strictly and formally ordinary “if-then” statements can be described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
